# Hwee Shan Wong

Software Engineer



#### About me

Hi, my name is Hwee and currently a software engineer in Natwest Group. I am passionate about developing tools and products to boost engineering experience. I have experience in delivering microservices using the twelvefactor app methodology, designing event-driven architecture and implementing infrastructure solutions and services.

Grew up trilingual (English, Mandarin, Malay).

#### Skills



#### Contact





+44 7424 586 826

HweeWong

# Experience

### **Software Engineer**

Natwest Group, Edinburgh | since April 2018

- · Automated the onboarding process to developer tools. Reduced cycle time from 48 hrs to 5 mins.
- Delivered Spring Boot Java microservices in event-driven architecture and have deep understanding of the system design.
- Actively engaged in system design decisions/architecture. Collaborated closely with customers/SMEs in agile development.
- Cultivated behaviour-driven and test-driven development within the team which enhanced system reliability and team's devops metrics. KPI
- 50% reduction in software development cycle time.
- Drove infrastructure and tooling improvements. Presented proof of concepts for various authentication/authorisation modules for tools.
- Mentoring junior engineers and continuously building best practices within the team such as codifying workflow using plantuml.

### **Technology Service Analyst**

Natwest Group, Edinburgh | Sep 2017 - Apr 2018

- Responsible for migrating server data from bespoke tools to standardised ServiceNow Configuration Management Database for better consolidation of enterprise data.
- Automated data gathering and validation process for the migration work to make sure data quality was high and consistent.
- Drove the implementation of agile ways of working in my team through creation of short-term, manageable goals and Kanban boards.

### **Chemical Engineer**

Merck, Sharp & Dohme (MSD), Newcastle | Aug 2015 - Sep 2016

- Supported technical operations in solid-dose tablet production facility and operated within GMP standards.
- Solved process deviations and problems by identifying root causes using Lean Six Sigma methodologies.



#### Education

MEng Chemical Engineering with Industrial Experience, University of Manchester

Sep 2013 - Jun 2017 First Class Honors

A Levels, Taylor's College

Jan 2012 - Jun 2013 4A\* in Chemistry, Biology, Physics, Mathematics



#### Contributions

## Women In Tech Secretariat

Actively supporting gender balance within workplace. Running python workshops to promote software development.

#### STEM Ambassador

Encouraging students to appreciate Science, Technology, Engineering and Math (STEM) subjects by engaging them in interesting experiments and sharing Edinburgh and Glasgow work experience.

# **STV Big Scot Quiz** Volunteer

Volunteered to assist and coordinate the running of a major, highprofile charity event that was held concurrently in which raised £35,000.